<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>home</title>
    <link>~dw3zn/</link>
    <description>Recent content on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2022 by Dane Williamson. &lt;a href=&#39;~dw3zn/privacy&#39;&gt;Privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 15:10:15 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="~dw3zn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Variational Autoencoders</title>
      <link>~dw3zn/posts/vae/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 15:10:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>~dw3zn/posts/vae/</guid>
      <description> Inference Generation ELBO Reparameterizatio Trick </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximum Likelihood Estimation</title>
      <link>~dw3zn/posts/mle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>~dw3zn/posts/mle/</guid>
      <description>Maximum Likelihood Estimation Likelihood Likelihood describes the joint probability of observed data, x as a function of the parameters, $\theta$ of a statistical model. The likelihood is NOT a probability density function of the parameters. An intuitive way to consider the likelihood is as equal to the probability density of the outcome, x when the true value of the parameter is $\theta$.
$\mathcal{L}$ is a probability density over x NOT $\theta$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>~dw3zn/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 13:23:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>~dw3zn/teaching/</guid>
      <description> Courses Taught CS 6316 - Machine Learning (Spring 2022) CSCI 120 - Introduction to Computer Science (Fall 2017, Spring 2018) CSCI 150/151 - Programming I &amp;amp; Programming I Lab (Fall 2019, Spring 2020) CSCI 250/251 - Programming II &amp;amp; Programming II Lab (Fall 2018, Spring 2020) CSCI 287 - Data Structures (Fall 2019, Spring 2020) CSCI 296 - Web Programming (Fall 2017, Spring 2018) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Inference</title>
      <link>~dw3zn/posts/bp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>~dw3zn/posts/bp/</guid>
      <description>Bayesian Inference Bayesian Inference is an approach to statistical inference which utilises Bayes&amp;rsquo; theorem to provide updates for the probability of an outcome as new information becomes available. The mathematical formulation for Bayes theorem is quite ubiquituous and no doubt you have seen it before, however it is stated here for completeness:
$$ p (z \mid x) = \frac{p(x \mid z) \cdot p(z)}{p(x)} $$
Simple right? Perhaps not so much to the unitiated to whom this equation may seem very strange and as such here is a breakdown of what these terms actually mean:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variational Inference</title>
      <link>~dw3zn/posts/vi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>~dw3zn/posts/vi/</guid>
      <description>What is Variational Inference? Variational Inference is a technique used in Bayesian Statistics to approximate $p ( z \mid x)$ the conditional density of an unknown variable, z given an observed variable, x through optimization. To find this approximate density:
select a family of densities, $\mathscr{D}$ over the latent variables. Each member of the family q(z) $\in \mathscr{D}$ is a candidate approximation to the true density. The optimization problem is then to find the member of this family which is closest in Kullback-Leibler (KL) divergence to the conditional density of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>~dw3zn/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>~dw3zn/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Computer Science PhD student at the University of Virginia, co-advised by Matthew Dwyer and Yangfeng Ji. I am a member of both the LESS Lab and ILP-Lab .
Research Interests My research interests lie in the areas of Software Engineering, Natural Language Processing, Computer Vision and Interpretable Machine Learning. My work is focused on:
Using unsupervised learning techniques such as dimensionality reduction and clustering to interpret the latent representation space of large language models such as BERT and Convolutional Models such as ResNet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy policy</title>
      <link>~dw3zn/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>~dw3zn/privacy/</guid>
      <description>This is where the imprint should go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>~dw3zn/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>~dw3zn/publications/</guid>
      <description> Peer reviewed articles Cowart, G., Williamson, D., Farhat, N., &amp;amp; Lee, J.-S. (2019). Do Humans STILL Have a Monopoly on Creativity or Is Creativity Overrated? HCI. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
